M. Sinan Özcerit Data Analyst

E-mail: sozcerit@gmail.com
Phone: +49 176 41649661
Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/sozcerit
GitHub: github.com/sozcerit

SUMMARY

1+ years of experience in **Data Analysis**, **Data Manipulation**, **Data Visualization**, and **Business Intelligence**. Performed **data extraction** and **analysis** with **Python** libraries like **NumPy**, **Pandas**, **Matplotlib**, and **Seaborn**.

Experience with SQL, Google Spreadsheet and Tableau for data manipulation and visualization.

Able to translating results into understandable terms for the success of the organization and business decisions. Strong analytical, and creative thinking, problem-solving, and technical skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Mentor – Clarusway, USA (Remote)

May 2021 - Present

- Trained Tableau, leaded and reviewed Tableau projects.
- Provided technical guidance and mentoring to students to review and assist with projects and exercises.
- Participated in weekly live group mentoring sessions with an industry-experienced data analysts and completed in-depth capstone projects.
- Mastered skills in Python, SQL, Tableau, Google Spreadsheets, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Hypothesis Testing.
- Collected and cleaned large datasets with Python by utilizing SQL and MS SQL Server.
- Extracted, processed and analyzed complex datasets using advanced querying, visualization and analytics tools.

Office Assistant - Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey

July 2018 - April 2019

- Updated tracking spreadsheets with the latest information, revising and reorganizing archive records.
- Scheduled meetings and made periodic talks with attendees.
- Assisted alumni office and graduates, and spended time on conducting answering phone calls and meetings.
- Delivered clerical support by handling a range of routine and special requirements

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Data Analysis, Business Intelligence, Statistics, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Python, SQL, HTML & CSS, MS SQL Server, Tableau, Google Sheets, Linux, Git, Github
- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Scrum, Kanban, Jira, Agile Methodology

PROJECT

- Exploratory Data Analysis on traffic stops in Rhode Island Pandas, Matplotlib
- Data Visualization on Police Killing in US- Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Data Visualization on Bike Demand Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib
- E-Commerce Data and Customer Retention Analysis with SQL Microsoft SQL Server (Azure Data Studio)
- Central and Eastern Europe EDA Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Plotly
- Top Games on Google Play Store EDA Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Plotly

EDUCATION

Data Analyst Trainee – Clarusway – Virginia, USA

March 2021 – Sep 2021

German Course – Ruhr Uni – Bochum, Germany

March 2020 – Present

B.A.: Political Science – Bilkent University, Turkey

Sep 2016 - Aug 2020

- Received a comprehensive (tuition + monthly stipend) scholarship since managed to be among the first 5000 students in Turkey's local university placement exam.
- Received a merit-based scholarship from the State of the Republic of Turkey.

LANGUAGE COMPETENCIES

English: Advanced / C1

German: Upper Intermediate / B2

Turkish: Native Language